# **Ofosu Kingsley**

C/O Constant Dedo, P.O.Box 2066, CHNTS, Tanoso –Sunyani, Bono Region, Ghana + [233] 201-694-902 / 541-424-292 | kingsleyofosu@yahoo.com

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a results-driven software developer with more than 5 years of experience in desktop and web applications development. I also have a strong background in database administration.

I am an expert in devising tailored solutions to assist businesses achieve their goals in a variety of industries and a cyber security enthusiast.

I strongly believe that, developing good applications for organizations always contribute to putting those organizations ahead. I am flexible enough to work in a team, but also enjoy working independently. I also possess superb communication skills.

#### **SKILLS**

- Framework and Languages JavaScript, Node.js, Angular, React, Ionic, ASP.NET core MVC, C#, VB.NET and SQL.
- Up to date knowledge of HTML5 and CSS3.
- Development Environments Microsoft Visual Studio and Visual Studio Code.
- Database Applications MS SQL Server, MySQL and MongoDB.
- Operating Systems Windows, Linux and macOS.

- Troubleshooting computer hardware.
- Setting up, Configuring and troubleshooting of Basic LAN's.
- Installing and maintaining computer operating systems.
- Debugging and strong problemsolving skills.
- Setting up, Configuring and Installing of PC's and Printers.
- Sales and Marketing.
- Financial Accounting

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### ThinkWell Solutions Company Limited

Software Developer/Database Administrator

Sunyani – Bono Region, Ghana January, 2014 – May, 2019

- Designing, coding, debugging, testing and maintaining of Web/Desktop Applications.
- Designing, implementing and maintaining database for applications.
- Ensuring all applications meet the Software Requirement Specification.
- Testing applications developed by other development teams.

- Copyediting content for websites.
- Monitoring website and platform performance.
- Managing the hosting environment for websites and applications.
- Conducting training sessions for clients on the use of developed systems.

#### NATIONAL HEALTH INSURANCE SCHEME

Sunyani – Bono Region, Ghana September, 2013 – August, 2014

National Service Personnel

• Educating potential members on the importance of the scheme.

- Registration of new members to the scheme.
- Entering membership data and generating temporary cards for members.
- Assist in vetting of claims submitted by the scheme's accredited health facilities.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Catholic University College of Ghana**

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Sunyani – Bono Region, Ghana September, 2009 – August, 2013

#### PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

#### Pluralsight, Inc.

Used pluralsight.com, an amazing online education platform, to take courses offered by subject-matter experts, to acquire knowledge and skills in web development and cyber security.

- Developed a familiarity, solidified and enhanced my skills in JavaScript plus Node.js, Angular, React, HTML5 and CSS3.
- CompTIA Network+ courses Developed a familiarity with networking concepts, operations and procedures.
- CompTIA Security+ courses Learned how to install and configure systems to secure applications, networks and devices.
- CompTIA Cybersecurity Analyst (CySA+) courses Developed a familiarity with the
  configuration and use of threat detection tools, perform data analysis and interpret the
  results to identify vulnerabilities and risks to organizations.

# **REFERENCES**

DR. GYAASE PATRICK OHEMENG (DEAN)
FACULTY OF INFORMATION AND COMMUNICATION SCIENCES AND TECHNOLOGY
CATHOLIC UNIVERSITY COLLEGE OF GHANA

kgyaase@gmail.com

Tel: + [233] 244-852-893 / 506-547-731

MR. ADORFUL FRANCIS (HEAD OF BUSINESS)
THINKWELL SOLUTIONS COMPANY LIMITED
fr.andorful@gmail.com

Tel: + [233] 501-455-146